Patrick Hoehn

Broomfield, Co, 80021 | 815-441-4279 | ThePatrickHoehn@gmail.com <u>Github</u> | <u>patrickhoehn.dev</u> | <u>linkedIn</u>

Software Engineer

Full stack web developer with experience in Ruby and JavaScript programming languages with a background in retail operations and customer service. Has a strong, detailed, and organized approach to performing job duties and a self motivated individual that excels working in a collaborative team environment. Board game enthusiast and professional tech student - able to quickly learn and adjust to an ever changing environment to optimize personal output and efficiency.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Ruby on Rails, SQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, JavaScript, React, React Native, GIT, SASS, HTML, RESTful APIs,, Photoshop, Corel

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

DM Mapper - YouTube Demo | Front End Github | Back End Github

Allows users to build a complex interconnected fictional world in an organized and easily traversable fashion.

- Implemented JSON Web Tokens for server side auth.
- Utilized Bcrypt to encrypt the users information both server and client side.
- Used ActiveRecord to create complex table relationships on the backend server.
- Introduced React Hooks to reduce unnecessary classes and improve readability.

BibFox - YouTube Demo | Front End Github | Back End Github

Allows users to build and maintain a virtual shelf of books that they currently own and find the locations of library share kiosks on Google Maps.

- Google Maps API and Google-Map-React library to customize the visuals of Google Maps.
- SASS to organize and improve the readability of CSS styling.
- React Router to give the appearance of a multi-page app.
- Followed the MVC architectural pattern and RESTful routing conventions

Board Game MeetUp - YouTube Demo | Front End Github | Back End Github

Brief description of the app's functionality and purpose

- Custom built RESTful API backend to store information
- Built in Vanilla JS to solidify JS fundamentals

EXPERIENCE

Engraver, The Watch Movement, Denver, Co. 06/2018 - present

Business partner and watch and jewelry engraver

Shipping and Receiving, Hyde Park, Denver, Co. 06/2018 - 10/2019

- Oversaw and processed all incoming and outgoing jewelry for the companies 4 locations while maintaining detailed records due to high value of items
- Implemented and trained receiving staff on new company wide software

Operations Manager, **Shane Co**, Greenwood Village, Co. 06/2014 - 06/2018

- Trained and managed the Customer Service team to provide excellent service. Planned and executed team events to build morale and to reduce turnover.
- Managed over \$7 Million of store merchandise including weekly inventories and Sales associate training on proper handling and processes.
- Oversaw shipping processes to ensure accuracy and efficiency.

EDUCATION

Flatiron School 2019 - 2020

Fully immersive 15 week, in person, full time 9-5 programming course that taught the methodology of Full Stack Web Development utilizing Ruby on Rails and JavaScript/React program languages.

Quantum Helicopters 2014-2015

Full time schooling over a 3 month period where I obtained a private helicopter license for non-turbine aircrafts.